以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
所以这是一个非常重要的讲座
so this is a pretty key lecture this
讲座是关于主要成分的
lecture is about principle component
分析PCA是其中的主要工具
analysis PCA which is a major tool in in
了解数据矩阵是什么
understanding a matrix of data so what
什么是PCA关于首先让我们
what is PCA about well first of all let
我记得那是什么意思
me remember what was the whole point of
昨天的讲座少了一些
less yesterday's lecture the singular
价值分解任何矩阵a
value decomposition that any matrix a
可以被分成一等级
could be broken into are rank one pieces
或者是矩阵的等级和每个
or being the rank of the matrix and each
你有V转置的时间和
piece has you times of V transpose and
好的特殊之处在于用户
the good special thing is the user
正交，也是V的
orthonormal and also the V's are also
正常确定，所以这是整个矩阵，但
normal ok so that's the whole matrix but
我们有一个很大的矩阵，我们希望得到
we have a big matrix and we want to get
重要的信息不是
the important information out of it not
所有信息和人们都说如果
all the information and people say if if
如果你已经学会了机器学习
in in machine learning if you've learned
你没有的所有训练数据
all the training data you haven't
真的学到了什么
learned anything really
你只是喜欢把它全部复制到你身上
you've just like copied it all in you
神经网络的全部意义
the whole point of of neural nets and
机器学习的过程就是
the process of machine learning is to
了解有关数据的重要事实
learn important facts about the data and
现在我们处于最基本的阶段
now here we're at the most basic stage
那个和我声称重要的
of that and I claim that the important
有关矩阵的事实在其中
facts about the matrix are in its
最大k奇异值最大k
largest k singular values the largest k
我们可以把k等于1的碎片告诉我们
pieces we can take k equal 1 would tell
我们是最大的单件，但也许我们
us the largest single piece but maybe we
有空间和计算能力来处理
have space and computing power to handle
一百块所以我会把k等于
a hundred pieces so I would take k equal
100 the
矩阵可能已经排了数千，所以我
matrix might have ranked thousands so I
声称，K是最好的，现在这里的
claim that a K is the best now here's
今天的一个定理是K使用
the one theorem for today that a K using
SVD的第一批K片
the first the first K pieces of the SVD
是等级K的最佳近似值
is the best approximation to a of rank K
所以我会把它写下来就是这样
so I'll write that down so that's that
真的说为什么SVD完美没问题
really says why the SVD is perfect okay
所以那个声明说如果是的话
so that's that statement says that if if
是另一个矩阵有等级K然后
be another matrix has rank K then the
从A到B的距离是你的错误
distance from A to B the error you're
只使用B就是错误
making in just using B that error is
大于或等于错误你
greater than or equal to the error you
做出最好的指导，这是一个
make for the best guidance so that's a
非常直白的事实
pretty straightforward beautiful fact
并且它可以追溯到的人谁
and it goes back to people who
首先发现了SVD
discovered the SVD in the first place
但后来有几位心理学家给了
but then a couple of psychologists gave
在后来的论文中经常提供证明
a proof in a later paper and it's often
称为Eckert年轻定理
called the Eckert young theorem
那个定理不是那个
there's the theorem isn't that
直截了当，假设是
straightforward and the hypothesis is
直截了当，但非常好
straightforward that's pretty nice but
当然，我们必须考虑为什么会这样
of course we have to think why is it
为什么它是真的并赋予意义
true why is it true and to give meaning
对于定理，我们必须说出这些
to the theorem we have to say what these
双杠是你知道的吗？
double bars are do you know the right
这个名称，以便双杠
name for this so that double bar around
矩阵称为矩阵的范数
a matrix is called the the norm of the
我必须说，矩阵是常态
matrix the norm so I have to say
关于矩阵规范的东西
something about matrix norms
这有多大是衡量有多大的尺度
how big is that's a measure of how big
它是，我要说的是
it is and what I have to say is
a有许多不同的衡量标准
there are many different measures of a
矩阵有多大矩阵让我
matrix how large that matrix is let me
今天告诉你三个可能
tell you for today three possible
矩阵的测量方式如此不同
measures of a matrix so different ways
测量和我，我会称之为矩阵
to measure and me I'll call the matrix
只是一个可能，但我会申请
just a maybe but then I'm gonna apply
衡量减去B和减去
the measure to a minus B and to a minus
一个K和显示，这是小
a K and show that that is the smaller
好的，所以我要告诉你关于
okay so I'm on to tell you about the
关于一些可能的规范的规范
norm of a about some possible norms of a
实际上我将要采取的规范
and actually the norms I'm going to take
今天将有这个特别的
today will be will have this special
他们可以找到计算的功能
feature that they can be found computed
通过他们的奇异价值让我
by their singular values so let me
提到的是l2规范
mention the the l2 norm that is the
最大的奇异值，所以这是一个
largest singular value so that's an
排序的重要措施
important measure of the sort of the
矩阵的大小我在这里说话是的
size of a matrix I'm talking here yeah
关于一般M乘n矩阵sigma
about a general M by n matrix a sigma
一个是经常是一个重要的规范
one is the is an important norm often
称为l2规范，那就是那个地方
called the l2 norm and that's where that
索引2去哦我应该真的开始
index 2 goes oh I should really start
用向量规范的向量然后
with vectors norms of vectors and then
建立两个矩阵规范让我做
build two norms of matrices let me do
这方面的向量规范
norms of vectors over on this side the
l2矢量的范数我们知道那是什么
l2 norm of a vector do we know what that
这是常规的长度
is that's the regular length of the
我们都期待广场的矢量
vector that we all expect the square
v1的平方正方形到VN平方
root of v1 squared up to VN square the
斜边斜边的长度
hypotenuse the length of the hypotenuse
在n维空间中，即l2
in n-dimensional space that's the l2
正因为如此，以a的L1规范标准
norm because of that to the l1 norm of a
矢量只是加起来那些碎片
vector is just add up those pieces
没有平方和平方根
without squaring and square rooting them
只需添加它们就是l1规范
just add them that's the l1 norm
你可能会说我们为什么要这样做
and you might say why do we want to
规范还是有更多的规范让我
norms or there are more norms let me
再告诉你一个无限规范
just tell you one more the infinity norm
并有对的人;一个理由
and there's a reason for the one and the
两个和无穷大是最大的
two and the infinity is the largest of
野兽没关系
the beasts okay
在我不知道之前你有没有见过规范？
have you met norms before I don't know
这些是矢量规范，但也许你
these are vector norms but maybe you
已经遇到了我们将要有矩阵
have met then we're going to have matrix
规范，也许会有新的，所以这是
norms that maybe will be new so this is
我们通常会想到的规范但是
the norm that we usually think of but
这个真的变了
this one has become really really
很重要，让我告诉你原因
important and let me tell you just why
然后我们的后面的章节
and then we'll a later section of the
本课程的笔记和后续讲座
notes and a later lecture in this course
我们将开发这个开发这个
we'll develop that develop this this is
l1范数所以这是l2l1和L.
the l1 norm so this is l2 l1 and L
无限有啥特别之处
infinity so what's special about this
一个好，它刚刚结束，它是
one well it just turned out and it was
只发现你知道我们的
only discovered you know in our
你最小化一些的生命周期
lifetimes that when you minimize some
使用你所在的l1范数的函数
function using the l1 norm you're in a
最小化一些说信号噪音或
minimize some say signal noise or
无论如何最小化某些功能
whatever you minimize some function if
你使用l1获胜的矢量了
you use l1 the winning vector the
最小化矢量变得稀疏
minimizing vector turns out to be sparse
什么稀疏意味着稀疏意味着什么
and what a sparse mean sparse means
我当时以某种方式大多数是0组件
mostly 0 components somehow when I
在l2中最小化哪个是
minimize in l2 which which is
历史上可以追溯到高斯了
historically goes back to Gauss the
有史以来最伟大的时数学家
greatest mathematician of all time when
你最小化你做的事情
you minimize something in l2 you do
最小的方块，你发现那个人
least squares and you find that the guy
给你最小的东西有很多
that gives you the minimum has a lot of
小数字很少
little numbers a lot of little
组件，因为当你平方那些
components because when you square those
小家伙，他们
little ones they they
不伤害很多，但女生如此盛会没
don't hurt much but gals so galas didn't
至少l1规范有不同
do least l1 norm that has different
命名基础追求而且它来了
names basis pursuit and and it comes
进入信号处理和传感权利
into signal processing and sensing right
然后发现如果你
and then it was discovered that if you
最小化，因为我们会在那个规范中看到你
minimize as we'll see in that norm you
令人惊讶地得到了获胜的矢量
amazingly get the winning vector has
多大多是零和优势
much mostly zeros and the advantage of
那就是你可以理解它是什么
that is that you can understand what its
组件是很多小的组件
components are the one with many small
你不喜欢他们的组件
components you're like he have no
该答案的解释，但为
interpretation for that answer but for
答案只有一些非零
an answer that just has a few nonzero
组件你真的看到了什么
components you really see what's
发生，然后这是一个重要的
happening and then this is a important
一个也好，现在我要转向
one too ok ok now I'm gonna turn just to
那么规范的特性是什么呢？
so what's the property of a norm well
你可以看到C次的规范
you can see that the norm of C times a
向量只乘以6或11或
vector is just multiplying by 6 or 11 or
减去pi或C的大小
minus pi or whatever is the size of C
规范有很好的属性他们
norms have that nice property they're
他们是同质的，或者无论如何
they're homogeneous or whatever word if
你仔细考虑你应该加倍的矢量
you mull the vector you should double
那个长度加倍的规范
the norm that double the length that
有道理然后重要
makes sense and then the important
属性是那个着名的三角形
property is that is the famous triangle
不平等，如果你是V和W
inequality that if you if V and W are
三角形的两边你拿走了
two sides of a triangle and you take the
V的规范并加上W的规范
norm of V and add to the norm of W the
双方得到的不仅仅是直线
two sides you get more than the straight
沿斜边的规范是的，所以那些
norm along the hypotenuse yeah so those
是我们需要的属性和与
are properties that we require and and
并且，事实上，规范的
and and the fact that the norm is
这是积极的，我不会写下来
positive which is I won't write down but
这很重要，所以那些
it's important to okay so those are
规范和那些也适用于
norms and those will apply also to
领班
maitre
Norm是如此，如果我加倍我想要的矩阵
Norm's so if I double the matrix I want
加倍其规范，当然也是如此
to double its norm and of course that
适用于墓葬规范和实际上
works for the tomb norm and actually
大概如此三角不等式
probably so the triangle inequality for
这种规范是最大的
this norm is saying that the largest
加号B两个矩阵的奇异值
singular value of a plus B two matrices
小于或等于最大的单数
is less or equal to the largest singular
a的值加上最大的奇异值
value of a plus the largest singular
B的价值，这是我们不会采取的
value of B and that's we we won't take
上课时间来检查它
class time to check minor it
这样的直截了当的事情
straightforward things like that
所以现在我要继续这样做
so now I'm gonna continue with that
我想告诉你的三个规范
three norms that I want to tell you
关于这是一个非常重要的一个再
about that's a very important one then
还有另一个被命名为的标准
there's another norm that's named as an
F和它的名字来自BGnaeus
F and it's named after fro B Gnaeus
对于那个很抱歉
sorry about that
什么是规范所关注的规范
and what is that norm that norm looks at
矩阵中的所有条目就像
all the entries in the matrix just like
它是一个长矢量并将它们平方
it was a long vector and squares them
所有并以某种方式将它们加起来
all and adds them up so in a way it's
就像矢量的两个标准一样
like the two norm for a vector it's so
平方或我应该放平方根
the squared or shall I put square root
也许我应该是它的平方根
maybe I should it's the square root of
矩阵中的所有小人物
all the little people in in the matrix
所以将1N的平方加上下一一个21
so a 1 n squared plus the next a 2 1
平方等等你终于到了M.
squared and so on you finally get to a M
ñ平方你你你刚才对待
N squared you you all you just treat the
矩阵就像一个长向量并采取这个
matrix like a long vector and take this
平方根就像这样
square root just just like so that's
这就是弗罗贝尼乌斯的规范然后
that's the Frobenius norm and then
终于没不那么有名的是
finally not not so well known is
更像是L的东西
something that's more like L one it's
称核规范
called the nuclear norm
而不是所有的教员都知道
and not all the faculty would know about
这个核规范所以是它的总和
this nuclear norm so it is the sum of
我想是奇异值的西格玛
the Sigma of the singular values I guess
它们就是我们所在的地方
there are of them so that's where we
会停下来哦好吧
would stop oh okay
所以这三个规范现在为什么要这样做
so those are three norms now why why do
我选择这三个规范和
I pick on those three norms and and
对于那些人来说，这是重点
here's the point that though for those
三个规范这个陈述是真的我
three norms this statement is true I
可以制定其他矩阵规范
could cook up other matrix norms for
这本是行不通的，但这些
which this wouldn't work but for these
三个高度重要的规范这个
three highly important norms this
EckhartJung声称最接近
Eckhart Jung statement that the closest
等级K近似值来自于
rank K approximation is found from the
先是K件，是的，你看到的是
first K pieces yeah you see that's a
好事，因为这就是我们
good thing because this is what we
从SVD计算，现在我们已经解决了
compute from the SVD so now we've solved
我们发现了近似问题
an approximation problem we found the
Benham最好的B是K和重点
Benham the best B is a K and the point
是否可以使用所有这些
is it could use all the any of those
规范所以会有一个好人
norms so there would be a well somebody
终于想出了一个证据
finally came up with a proof that would
，做所有这三个准则一次在
that does all three norms at once in the
笔记我做一个分开
notes I do that one separately from
Frobenius，实际上我在麻省理工学院找到了
Frobenius and actually I found in an MIT
论文只是我刚读了一门课程
thesis just I was just reading a course
六篇博士论文和作者是谁
six PhD thesis and the author who's
明天和周五的演讲
speaking tomorrow in and or Friday in in
idss博士cerebro找到了一个很好的新证明
idss dr. cerebro found a nice new proof
弗罗贝尼乌斯，它在笔记中
of Frobenius and it's in the notes as
以及更老的证据你知道吗
well as the an older proof okay you know
我在这里说话时我不太确定
as I talk here I'm not too sure whether
这对我来说是必不可少的
it is essential for me to go through the
证明
proof
或者在l2范数内，需要一半
either in the l2 norm which takes half a
笔记中的页面或Frobenius中的页面
page in the notes or in the Frobenius
需要更多的规范，我宁愿你看
norm which takes more I'd rather you see
重点在于这些
the point the point is that in these
规范，现在有什么特别之处
norms and now what is special about
这些依赖的矩阵规范
these norms of a matrix these depend
只有他们的西格玛只有这个哦
only on their Sigma's only on this oh
我会完成那句话，因为它是
I'll finish that sentence because it was
这些规范仅仅依赖于这些规范
true these these norms depend only on
奇异的价值吧
the singular values right
那一个至少只取决于一个
that one at least depends only on a
奇异值这是最大的一个
singular value it's the largest one this
一个是这一切的总和
one is the sum of them all this one
进入Netflix比赛
comes into the Netflix competition by
这是赢得正确规范的方式
the way this was the right norm to win
在Netflix的数不胜数美元
zillion dollars in the Netflix
竞争那么Netflix就是这么说的
competition so what did Netflix put it
做过电影的数学竞赛
did a math competition it had movie
来自许多Netflix的偏好
preferences from many many Netflix
订阅者将他们的排名归结为
subscribers they gave their ranking to a
一堆电影，但当然他们
bunch of movies but of course they
没见过没有人见过全部
hadn't seen No none of them had seen all
电影所以排名矩阵
the movies so the matrix of rankings
你有怨恨和矩阵的地方
where you had the rancor and the matrix
是一个非常大的矩阵，但它有
was a very big matrix but it's got
如果怨恨没有看到错过的条目
missing entries if the rancor didn't see
电影
the movie
他不是他或她没有这么排名
he isn't he or she isn't ranking it so
关于Netflix的想法是什么呢？
what's the idea about Netflix so they
提供了一百万美元的奖金
offered a like a million dollar prize
还有很多数学和计算机科学
and a lot of math and computer science
人们为这个奖项而奋战
people fought for that prize and over
他们得到的年份更高929394
the years they got like higher 92 93 94
正确的百分比，但事实证明
percent right so but it turned out that
你最不得不这样做
this was well you had to in the end you
不得不用一点心理学的方法
had to use a little psychology of how
人们投了票，所以部分是关于
people voted so it was partly about
人类心理学，但它也是一个非常
human psychology but it was also a very
不完整的大矩阵问题
large matrix problem with an incomplete
矩阵一个不完整的矩阵，所以它
matrix an incomplete matrix and so it
已经完成，你必须身材
had to be completed you had to figure
什么会
out what would
如果他的话，排名者已经对这个帖子说过了
ranker have said about the post if he
没有看到它，但排名你知道
hadn't seen it but had ranked you know
其他几部电影像所有的
several other movies like all the
总统的男人或任何给予的人
President's Men or whatever given a
排名到你必须的那个和那个
ranking to those you have to and that's
当然是一个推荐系统
a recommender system of course that's
这是怎么得到建议的
what that's how you get recommendations
来自亚马逊
from from Amazon
他们有一个很大的矩阵计算
they've got a big matrix calculation
在这里，如果你已经买了几个
here and if you've bought a couple of
数学书他们会告诉你的
math books they're gonna tell you about
更多的数学书比你更想
more math books more than you want to
知道的没事
know all right
是的，所以无论如何它只是结果
yeah okay so anyway it just turned out
这个规范是正确的
that this norm was the right one to
最小化我不能给你所有的
minimize I can't give you all the
Netflix的竞争的详细信息，但
details of the Netflix competition but
这被证明是正确的标准来
this turned out to be the right norm to
至少做一个最小的问题
do a minimum problem a best not least
正方形这些正方形会看一些
squares these squares would look at some
其他规范，但最好的核规范
other norm but a best nuclear norm
完成矩阵和现在
completion of the matrix and and and now
这是一个如此现在它被放了很多
it's a so now it's being put to much
用于MRI磁场的更严重的用途
more serious uses from for MRI magnetic
当你离开时，你知道的共鸣
resonance stuff you know when you're go
并且让你这是一个嘈杂的系统但是
in and get you it's a noisy system but
你得到它它给出了一个很好的图片
you get it it gives a excellent picture
发生了什么，所以我只是
of of what's going on so so I'll just
在这里写netflix就可以了
write netflix here so it gets in this
然后核磁共振有啥关于点
and then MRIs so what's the point about
核磁共振成像，如果你没有，如果你长时间停留
MRIs so if you don't if you stay in long
够了，你得到了你得到了你
enough you gotta come you get a you got
所有的数字都不是没有的
all the numbers aren't any there isn't
缺少数据，但如果你是一个孩子
missing data but if you was with a child
你可能想让孩子进来
you might want to just have the child in
几分钟然后这还不够
for a few minutes then that's not enough
得到一个完整的图片，你有一个
to get a complete picture and you have a
你的矩阵中缺少数据
and missing data in your matrix of in
你的MRI中的图像是这样的
your your in the image from the MRI so
当然，你必须完成
then of course you've got to complete
那个矩阵你必须填写什么
that matrix you have to fill in what
MRI将会看到什么
would the what would the MRI have seen
在那些看起来没有的位置
in those positions where it didn't look
足够长，又是一个核规范
long enough and again a nuclear norm is
好的，好的
the good one for that okay
所以那里会有一个整体
so there's there there will be a whole
关于规范的部分可能就在其中
section on norms maybe just about in in
现在很好，所以我不会
stellar by now okay so I'm not going to
让我说一下这是什么
let me just say like what does this what
这会告诉我们这是什么意思吗？
does this say what does this tell us
所以我只是举一个例子，也许我会
so I'll just give an example maybe I'll
从这个例子开始
take start start with the example that's
在笔记中假设K是2所以我是
in the notes suppose K is 2 so I'm
在所有等级两个矩阵中寻找
looking of among all rank two matrices
并假设我的矩阵是4321和所有
and suppose my matrix is 4 3 2 1 and all
剩下的零点，它是排名4
the rest zeroes diag and it's a rank 4
矩阵我可以看到它的奇异值
matrix I can see it singular values
坐在那里
there sitting there
这些将是奇异值和
those would be the singular values and
本征值和一切
the eigen values and everything of
当然，现在这将是一个2会是什么
course now what would be a 2 what would
是秩2的最佳近似值
be the best approximation of Rank 2 to
从这个意义上说，这个矩阵是
that matrix in in this sense to be
完成了将要做的事情
completed what would a to do yeah it
将是4和3它将挑选两个
would be 4 and 3 it would pick the two
最大的，所以我在寻找一个K-8，这是
largest so I'm looking at a k-8 this is
2斗篷所以它必须有一个2级
cape of the 2 so it has to have a rank 2
这已经获得了最大的排名
this has got rank for the biggest pieces
是那些
are those
好吧所以这件事说如果我有的话
okay so this thing says that if I had
任何其他矩阵B它会更进一步
any other matrix B it would be further
远离比这家伙说，这
away from a than this guy says that this
是最接近的，我只是想能
is the closest and I just like could
你能想到一个可能的矩阵吗？
could you think of a matrix that could
可能越走越排至
possibly be closer and be ranked to that
排名二是棘手的事情了
rank two is the tricky thing the the
等级2的矩阵形成一种疯狂
matrices of Rank 2 form a kind of crazy
如果我将Rank2矩阵添加到Rank2，则设置
set if I add a Rank 2 matrix to a Rank 2
矩阵
matrix
可能排名高达4，所以
probably the rank is up to 4 so so the
等级2矩阵都是浮动的
rank 2 matrices are all kind of floating
在他们自己的一点点
around and little in their own little
角落这看起来是最好的一个但是
corners this looks like the best one but
在笔记中我建议你可以
in the notes I suggest well you could
获得排名交配秩我可以或
get a rank to mate a rank I could or
怎么样B这个BI怎么样？
what about B what about this B I for
这家伙我可以靠近了
this guy I could get closer
也许不是确切的，但可能更接近
maybe not exact but closer maybe by
服用3.53.5哦但我只想用
taking 3.5 3.5 oh but I only want to use
排名很好，我只得排名2
rank well I've only got to rank 2 to
玩耍所以我最好把它变成一个
play with so I better make this into a
我必须要把它变成一个
right I have to like make this into a
排名第一，然后是2和1
rank one piece and then the 2 and the 1
所以你看到的我已经什么，我想我
so you see what I've what I thought of I
以为男人也许这就像更好
thought man maybe that's better like on
对角线我越来越近我了
the diagonal I'm coming closer well I'm
没有完全在这里，但后来
not getting it exactly here but then
我还有一个可以玩，我会
I've got one left to play with and I'll
把这可能1.5放在这里好吧这是一个
put maybe 1.5 down here ok so that's a
等级2矩阵2小等级和等级
rank 2 matrix 2 little rank ones and on
对角线它更好三分
the diagonal it's better three-point
五点我只丢1/2点一点
fives I'm only missing by 1/2 one point
5s我失踪了一半，所以我只是
5s I'm missing by half so I'm only
在对角线上失踪了一半
missing by half on the diagonal where
这家伙失踪了2所以也许我已经失踪了
this guy was missing by 2 so maybe I've
找到了更好的东西，但我不得不付钱
found something better but I had to pay
这些东西的价格已经濒临死亡
a price of these things off the dying
保持排名低，他们杀了我
to keep the ranked low and they kill me
所以将远离a
so that be will be further away from a
如果我计算了减去B和的错误
the error if I computed a minus B and
计算它的规范我会看到更大
computed its norm I would see bigger
所以你看，比大于a-a-ÿà更大
than bigger than a - a - ÿà so you see
那是那个定理的重点
the point of the theorem that's that's
真的是我想说的是
really what I'm trying to say that it is
不太明显你可能会感觉良好
not obvious you may you may feel well
选择四和三是完全明显的
it's totally obvious pick four and three
还有什么可以做到的，但这取决于
what else could do it but it depends on
规范等等所以它不是库尔特
the norm and so on so it's not a Kurt
年轻人不得不考虑一个证明和其他
Young had to think of a proof and other
人们也没关系，这样现在，但你
people too okay so that's now but you
也可以说我开始说的对象
could say also say object that I started
这里有一个对角矩阵
with a diagonal matrix here that's so
特别，但我想说的是
special but what I want to say is the
对角矩阵并不那么特别
diagonal matrix is not that special
因为我可以接受，所以让我怀疑
because I could take a so let me doubt
只要调用这个对角矩阵D哦
just call this diagonal matrix D oh let
我把它称为西格玛给它另一种
me call it Sigma to give it another sort
适当的名字，如果我想的话
of appropriate name so like if I thought
矩阵我想说的是这个
of matrices what I want to say is this
可能是西格玛基质和有
could be the Sigma matrix and there
可能是你左边的一个和一个
could be a you on the left of it and a
西格玛在右边就这样了
Sigma on the right of it so so about a
suSigmaV转置所以这是我的Sigma
su Sigma V transpose so this is my Sigma
这就像任何正交矩阵U.
and this is like any orthogonal matrix U
这就像任何V转置权一样
and this is like any V transpose right
我只是说这里还有很多
I'm just saying here's a whole lot more
矩阵只有一个矩阵，但现在
matrices there's just one matrix but now
我有所有这些矩阵使用
I have all these matrices with use
乘以左边和V转置
multiplying on the left and V transpose
在右边这样，我问你这个
on so on the right and I ask you this
质疑什么是奇异的价值观
question what are the singular values of
这个矩阵在这里是奇异值
that matrix a here the singular values
很清楚四三两个和一个
were clear four three two and one
这个的奇异价值是什么？
what are the singular values of this
矩阵a，当我乘以a
matrix a when I've multiplied by a
两边的正交人是一个
orthogonal guy on both sides that's a
关键问题是什么是单数
key question what are the singular
价值一四四二一
values of that one four three two one
没有改变为什么那是因为
didn't change why is that because the
奇异值是因为这有
singular values are the because this has
SVD形式正交对角线
a SVD form orthogonal times diagonal
正交和对角线的时间
times orthogonal and that diagonal
包含我所知的奇异值
contains the singular values what I'm
说这可能是一个小时的琐碎
saying is that might an hour trivial
这里的小例子实际上就是全部
little example here actually was all
四乘具有这些奇异的四肢
four by fours that have these singular
价值我可以解决我的问题
values I could my whole problem is
正交e不变tamasic我会
orthogonal e invariant tamasic I would
当我乘以U或V时说
say when I multiply by U or a V
转置或两者都没有问题
transpose or both the problem doesn't
改变规范不改变是啊那是一个
change norms don't change yeah that's a
点是的，我知道现在是这样的
point yeah I realize it now this is the
如果我将矩阵a乘以
point if I multiply the matrix a by by
正交矩阵U它具有全部
an orthogonal matrix U it has all the
相同的规范并没有改变常态
same norms doesn't change the norm
实际上这是真正的回归
actually that was true way back for
与该长度与该载体
vectors with with this length with this
长度
length
什么是关于矢量的交易假设我
what's the deal about vectors suppose I
假设我有一个向量V和我
suppose I have a vector V and I've
计算了它的斜边和规范
computed its hypotenuse and the norm and
现在我在同样的两个中看Q倍V
now I look at Q times V in that same two
规范什么是特别的
norm what's what's special about that
所以我拿了任何矢量V而且我知道什么
so I took any vector V and I know what
它的长度是斜边
it's length is hypotenuse
现在我乘以Q会发生什么
now I multiply by Q what happens to the
长度不变不变
length doesn't change doesn't change
正交矩阵，你可以想到它
orthogonal matrix you could think of it
就像旋转三角形一样
as just like rotating the triangle in
空间的斜边不会改变
space the hypotenuse doesn't change and
我们检查过，因为我们可以
we've checked that because we could you
知道检查是对它和
know the check is to square it and
你正在做QV转置QV和
and you're doing Q V transpose Q V and
你把它简化通常的方式，然后
you simplify it the usual way and then
你有Q转置Q等于
you have Q transpose Q equal the
身份，你是金色的，所以
identity and you're golden yeah so the
结果是你得到与V相同的答案
result is you get the same answer as V
所以让我把它放在句子中暂停
so let me put it in a sentence now pause
乘以该规范不会改变
multiplying the that norm is not changed
通过正交矩阵和这些规范是
by orthogonal matrix and these norms are
没有被正交矩阵改变
not changed by orthogonal matrices
因为如果我把a乘以一个
because if I multiply the a here by an
正交矩阵我有这个是我的
orthogonal matrix I I have this is my a
如果我乘以Q而我有Qu
if I multiply by by a Q and I have Q u
SigmaV转置，真正的是什么
Sigma V transpose and what is the really
qu是一个基本点
the underlying point that qu is an
正交矩阵和你一样好
orthogonal matrix just as good as you
那么，如果我把这个QA放下来会是Q
so what if I put this down QA would be Q
你使用西格玛V转换，现在我问
u Sigma V transpose and now I'm asking
你有什么奇特的价值
you what's the singular value
质量保证的分解，我希望我可以
decomposition for QA and I hope I may
实际上看到它是什么单数
actually see it what's the singular
QA的价值分解是什么
value decomposition of QA what are the
他们的价值观是什么
thing of their values what's the
对角矩阵只是看那里
diagonal matrix just look there for it
对角矩阵是西格玛，是什么
the diagonal matrix is Sigma what's the
V转置右侧
goes on the right of it the V transpose
它的左边是Qu
and what goes on the left of it is Q u
因为这是正交时间
because that's orthogonal times
在这个房间里正交每个人都有
orthogonal everybody in this room has to
知道如果我乘以两个正交
know that if I multiply two orthogonal
矩阵结果再次正交
matrices the result is again orthogonal
所以我可以乘以Q而且它只是
so I can multiply by Q and it only
影响U部分不是Sigma
affects that the U part not the Sigma
部分，所以它不会改变任何
part and so it doesn't change any of
那些
those
Norm没关系，所以没关系
Norm's okay so that's fine
这就是我想说的
that's what I wanted to say about the
埃克特年轻定理没有证明这一点但是
Eckert young theorem not proving it but
但希望能给你一个例子
but hopefully giving you an example
那意味着这是什么意思
there of what it means that that this is
接近那一个的最佳等级
the best rank to to approximate that one
还好，这样的背后PCA关键数学等等
okay so that's key math behind PCA so
现在我想缺口它不只是
now I have to want to notch it not just
不得不想告诉你有关PCA的事
have to but want to tell you about PCA
那是什么呢？
so what's what's that about
所以我们有一堆数据，我们想要
so we have a bunch of data and we want
看到这个让我拿出一堆数据
to see so let me take a bunch of data
一堆数据点说出了分数
bunch of data points say points in the
飞机所以我有一堆数据点
plane so I have a bunch of data points
在飞机上所以这是我的数据向量
in the plane so here's my data vector
第一个向量XY井X是一个好的
first vector X Y well X is that a good
也许V这些只是两个组成部分
maybe V one these are just two component
伙计我也是他们只是专栏
guys me too they're just columns with
两个组件，所以我只是在测量
two components so I'm I'm just measuring
喜欢高度和年龄，我想找到
like height and age and I want to find
身高与年龄的关系
the relationship between height and age
所以第一行是指高度
so the first row is meant is the height
我的数据和第二行是
of my data and the second row is the
所以这些都是如此，所以我说了一个
ages so these are so so I've got say a
很多人这些都是高度和
lot of people these are the heights and
这些是年龄，我有n分
these are the ages and I've got n points
在2d
in 2d
而且我想从中理解我
and I want to make sense out of that I
想要寻找这种关系
want to look for the relationship
高度和年龄之间我实际上
between height and age I'm actually
要寻找之间的线性关系
gonna look for a linear relation between
高度和年龄一点也好
height and age okay so first of all
这些是所有的地方，因此
these are all over the place so the
统计学家要做的第一步
first step that a statistician to does
是得到平均值为零得到平均值
is to get mean zero get the average to
为零所以这一切都是如此
be zero so what is so so all these
从第1行到处都是积分
points are all over the place from row 1
高度我减去平均值
the heights I subtract the average
高度所以这是我的矩阵
height so this is a the matrix I'm
真的要继续工作的是我的矩阵a
really going to work on is my matrix a
减去平均身高
minus the average height well in all
组件所以这是我减去的
components so this is a I'm subtracting
我正在减去这些平均值
I'm subtracting these a mean so average
身高是一个平均年龄哦
height an average age oh that was a
精彩的记谱法asubaaacan
brilliant notation a sub a can't be a
你看到矩阵做了什么
sub you see what the matrix has done
这个两个矩阵意味着它只是
this this matrix of two means it's just
刚刚制作的每一行现在增加了两行
just made each row of a now adds two now
如果我有一堆东​​西怎么办？
what if I have a bunch of things and
我减掉了他们的手段
I've subtracted off their means of the
平均值或平均值现在为零
mean or the average is now zero then
那些东西加起来就是我的权利
those things add up to zero right I'm
只是喜欢把这些点进入
just like brought these points into
像这里的东西，这就是年龄
something like here this is this is age
这是高度，让我们看看和通过
and this is height and let's see and by
减去它不再是不合理的
subtracting it no longer is unreasonable
有负面年龄
to have negative age
负高度，因为我是对的
negative height because I'm so right the
小孩子，当我减去它
little kids when I subtract it off the
平均年龄他们最终得到了
average age they ended up with a
消极的年龄，旧的老年人最终
negative age the old older ones ended up
仍然是积极的，不知怎的，我有一个
still positive and somehow I've got a
很多但很有希望
whole lot of points but hopefully
他们是他们的意思现在零你做
they're they're mean is now zero do you
看到我已经集中了
see that I've since I've centered the
零零的数据，我正在寻找
data at zero zero and I'm looking for
我在这里找什么呢？
what what am I looking for here I'm
寻找最适合我的路线
looking for the best line that's what I
想找到，这将是一个问题
want to find and that would be a problem
在PCA中，什么是最好的线性关系
in PCA what's the best linear relation
因为PCA是有限的PCA不是全部
because PCA is limited PCA isn't all of
无论如何深入学习整体
deep learning by any means the whole
深度学习的成功是最终的
success of deep learning was the final
经过一堆多年的实现
realization after a bunch of years that
他们必须具有非线性功能
they had to have a nonlinear function in
那里要去模型
there to to get to get to to model
严重的数据，但这里的PCA是线性的
serious data but here's PCA is a linear
生意，我正在寻找最好的
business and I'm looking for the best
你会说等一下
line and you will say wait a minute
我知道如何找到最好的线正好
I know how to find the best line just
使用这些正方形高斯做它不可能
use these squares Gauss did it can't be
都不好
all bad
但PCA和我正在给一个谈话
but PCA and and I was giving a talk in
纽约的时候，我只是学习
New York when I was just learning about
它和某人说你在做什么
it and somebody said what you're doing
PCA必须至少相同
with PCA has to be the same as least
正方形它找到了最好的线和我
squares it's finding the best line and I
知道不是，但我不知道怎么做
knew it wasn't but I didn't know how to
最好回答这个问题，现在回答
answer the question best and now at
至少我知道更好，所以最好的线路
least I know better so the best line in
最小二乘法可我提醒你
least squares can I remind you about
这些方块因为这并非最不重要
these squares because this is not least
方这些广场的最佳路线等等
square the best line of these squares so
我有一天
I have some day
积分，我有一个最好的路线
points and I have a best line that goes
通过它们和这些方块我
through them and and these squares I
并不总是将数据置于中心位置
don't always Center the data to mean
零，但我可以，但是做什么
zero but I could but what what what do
你在这些方格中最小化
you minimize in these squares least
如果你还记得那张照片中的方块
square if you remember the picture in
最小二乘的线性代数书
linear algebra books of least squares
你测量三个错误
you measure the errors like the three
错误，这是你错了多少
errors and it's how much you're wrong at
这三个点的是三个
those three points those are the three
错误
errors
一个X和B中的B之间的差异
a difference between a X and B the B
减去X你方，你加起来
minus a X that you square and you add up
这三个错误和有什么不同
those three errors and what's different
在这里，我的意思是有更多的积分，但
over here I mean there's more points but
那不是那个不重要的
that's not that's not the point that's
没有区别的区别是在
not the difference the difference is in
您正在垂直测量的PCA
PCA you're measuring perpendicular to
这条线你要加起来所有这些
the line you're adding up all these
小家伙正在盯着他们，所以你
little guys squaring them so you're
加上他们的方块并尽量减少
adding up their squares and minimizing
所以你看到的点是不同的
so the points you see it's a different
问题因此它有所不同
problem and therefore it has a different
回答这个，这个答案结果是
answer that and this answer turns out to
涉及到这个答案的SVDsigmaz
involve the SVD sigmaz where this answer
你记得从普通的线性
you remember from ordinary linear
代数只是当你减少你
algebra just when you minimize that you
得到了线索导致的等式
got to an equation the leads leads to
最佳X的一个等式也是如此
one equation for the best X so do you
记住是的，现在是什么
remember yeah what's what is it now
每个人都应该知道耶以及我的意思
everybody should know yeah well I mean
我们实际上会在这看到它
and we will actually see it in this
当然因为我们正在做的一部分
course because we're doing the part of
线性代数在这里我们还没有做到
linear algebra here we haven't done it
然而，再次告诉我什么是伙伴
yet though and tell me again what mate
Maitre是什么等式做的
what Maitre what equation do
我自己或那个问题a
myself or the for that problem a
转置X等于转置B
transpose a X had equal a transpose B
称为正规方程式的一部分
called the normal equations part of it
说这是在回归
says this is a regression in in
统计语言是一种回归
statistics language that's a regression
问题这是一个不同的问题好吧
problem this is a different problem okay
现在就这样，这涉及到他们
just so now so that involves well they
两者都涉及转置这种类型
both involve a transpose a that's sort
有趣的是因为你有一个
of interesting because you have a
矩形矩阵a然后更早或
rectangular matrix a and then sooner or
后来一个转置即将到来但是这个
later a transpose a is coming but this
涉及解决的线性系统
involves solving a linear system of
方程，速度非常快，我们将做到这一点
equations so it's fast and we will do it
这很可能是非常重要的
and it's very important it's probably
1806年最重要的应用
the most important application in 1806
但它是不一样的，因为这一个，这样
but it's not the same as this one so
这是目前在1806年也许是最后一天
this is now in 1806 maybe the last day
是PCA，所以我没有把这些信件
is PCA so I didn't put those letters
主成分分析PCA
principle component analysis PCA which
他汀类药物已经做了很长时间了
statins have been doing for a long time
这是我们没有做一些全新的
it's we're not doing something brand new
在这里，但结果是，我们因此如何
here but the result is that we so how
统计学家是否考虑过这一点
does the statistician think about this
问题或数据矩阵，如果你
problem or that data matrix what if you
有两行数据中的两个的矩阵
have a matrix of data two by two rows
和许多列这么多的样本
and many columns so many many samples
什么，我们所做的均值为0，这样的
what and we've made the mean 0 so that's
第一步统计学家拍摄静止
the first step a statistician take still
检查平均值下一步是什么
check on the mean what's the next step
统计学家还做了什么呢
what else does a statistician do with
用来衡量叹息的数据
data to measure how fit sighs there's
另一个号码有一个数字，
another number there's a number that
与均值一致，这是方差
goes with the mean and it's the variance
不知何故，均值和方差
the mean and the variance so somehow
我们要做差异，它会
we're going to do variances and it will
真的参与其中因为我们有两个
really be involved because we have two
数据集高度和年龄我们是
sets of data Heights and ages we're
真的会有协方差
really going to have the covariance
协方差矩阵，它将是2乘2
covariance matrix and it will be 2 by 2
因为它不仅会告诉我们
cause it will tell us not only the
高度的变化就是什么
variance in the heights that's what
统计学家会想到的第一件事
first thing a statistician would think
关于你了解一些小人物
about you know some small people some
大人物和年龄的变化但是
big people and variation in ages but
也是他们之间的联系
also the link between them
高度年龄对如何做
how are the height age pairs does does
更多的高度更多的年龄与更多
more height does more age go with more
高度，当然，它确实是这样的
height and of course it does that's the
整点这里，所以它的这个协方差
whole point here so it's this covariance
矩阵和协方差矩阵或
matrix and that covariance matrix or the
样本协方差矩阵给它一个
sample covariance matrix to give it a
全名是什么，所以只是触及
full name what's the so just touching on
这里有统计数据
statistics for a moment here
什么时候我们看到这个词
what's the when do we see that word
在名称中的样本是什么
sample in the in the name what is that
告诉我们它告诉我们这个
telling us it's telling us that this
矩阵是从样本中计算出来的
matrix is computed from the samples not
从理论概率
from a theoretical probability
分配我们可能有一个建议
distribution we might have a proposed
该高度遵循分布
distribution that the height follows the
高龄跟随年龄的年龄
a the age while height follows the age
通过一些公式，这将给我们一个
by some formula and that would give us a
理论上的差异我们正在做样本
theoretical variances we're doing sample
差异也称为经验
variances also called empirical
经验所说的协方差
covariance made empirical says
经验，这个词意味着从
empirical that word means from the
从数据信息，所以这就是
information from the data so that's what
我们这样做，它正是一列火车
we do and it is exactly a train a
aatranspose你必须将它标准化
a a transpose you have to normalize it
通过数据点的数量和
by the number of data points and and
然后出于某种原因最为人所知
then for some reason best known to
统计学家，它是n减1和
statisticians it's n minus 1 and of
当然，他们一定是正确的，他们已经
course they got to be right they've been
很长一段时间，它应该是n
around a long time and it should be n
减1，因为不知何故一度
minus 1 because somehow one degree of
我们采取了自由
freedom was accounted for when we took
拿走了那个平均为0的人
took away the one who made the mean 0
无论如何没有问题，但N减1
anyway no problem but but the N minus 1
不会影响我们的计算
is not going to affect our computation
在这里，这是告诉的矩阵
here that this is the matrix that tells
我们这就是我们，这就是我们所
us that's what we were that's what we've
得到了我们所拥有的
got to work with that's what we've got
使用矩阵aa转置
to work with the matrix a a transpose
然后我们就有这个问题所以我们
and then so we have this problem so we
有一个是的，我想我们真的有一个
have a yeah I guess we really have a
我们想找到的最小问题是的
minimum problem we want to find yeah
哪些问题是我们解决所以我们
what problem are we solving so our
问题不仅仅是广场不是没有
problem was not least squares not not
与这些方块相同，但是
the same as these squares similar but
不一样，我们想尽量减少
not the same we want to minimize so
我们正在寻找最好的路线
we're looking for that best line
我们的年龄等于C倍数
we're age equals some number C times the
高度时间ya或高度也许它会
height times ya or height maybe it would
把年龄放在这里更好
have been better to put age here and
高度在这里不，不，我们是因为他们是两个
height here no no we're cuz they're two
未知因此我正在寻找C我
unknowns so I'm looking for C I'm
寻找C号寻找
looking for the number C looking for the
C号，只有两分钟
number C and with just two minutes in
上课留下了那个数字C会是什么
class left what is that number C gonna
当我最终得到问题时
be when I finally get the problem stated
正确
properly
然后解决它，我要学习的是
and then solve it I'm gonna learn that
年龄与身高的最佳比例是西格玛
the best ratio of age to height is Sigma
1西格玛1，这就是那个
1 Sigma 1 that's so that's the one that
告诉我们这两者是如何联系的
tells us how those two are connected and
正交和什么是最好的
the orthogonal and what will be the best
是的，不，也许我没有回答
yeah well no maybe I didn't answer that
太对了，因为我在找我
too right because I'm looking for I'm
寻找指向的向量
looking for the vector that points in
正确的方式是啊，我很抱歉，我想
the right way yeah I'm sorry I think the
答案是它一定是那里的
answer is it's got to be there in the
SPD我认为这是你想要的矢量
SPD I think it's the vector you want
它是uu1的主要组成部分
it's a principal component uu 1 let's do
星期五，我希望你看到
that properly on Friday I hope you see
因为这就像第一步
because this was like the first step
远离线性的亮点
away from the highlights of linear
代数两个问题由内在解决
algebra two problems solved by the inner
代数和实际问题和我的
algebra and practical problems and my
aunt my point is that the SVD saw Z's
阿姨，我的观点是，SVD看到Z的
好的
okay